

BUSINESS DATA ANALYST

☑ jleyva82@gmail.com ८ (510) 586-52-60 ♀ Alameda California 94501 in Jesus-Leyva ♀ jleyvva82

SUMMARY

Analyst, mathematician, educator and all around nerd, with a passion for algorithmic data problem solving and visual representation for clear communication. All my educational, professional and interpersonal experiences have promoted positive growth mindset and attention to detail.

EDUCATION

Springboard 2019 to Current

Data Analytics Track

400+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 2 in-depth capstone projects. Mastered skills in analyzing business problems, data analysis, presenting business insights to different stakeholders, SQL, Python and data visualization.

University of California, Berkeley Bachelors of Arts Pure Mathematics Minor in Education

SKILLS

DATA ANALYSIS: SQL, PowerBI, Tableau, MS Excel, MS Access, SAP EPPM **ENGINEERING:** MATLAB, AutoCAD (mechanical design), Solidworks

PROGRAMMING: C++, Python 3, LaTeX, R

MATHEMATICS: Real and Complex Analysis, Computability, Set Theory, Discrete, Probability, Linear Algebra, Number Theory, Mathematica

EMPLOYMENT

PG&E (contract)

STAR Business / Data Analyst · San Ramon California

2020 to Current

- Data governance in SAP Electronic Project Portfolio Management (EPPM) and Electronic Document Routing System(EDRS) of authorization documents
- Use 63 critical data points from EPPM and EDRS to compile comprehensive reports of projects, assets and regions to California Public Utilities Commissions (CPUC) on a bi-yearly basis and as inquiries arise
- Use Excel and / or PowerBI in the development of live dashboards and other story telling visuals that analyze current status as well as a comparison to initial
 projections

Southern California Edison (contract)

Analyst Program / Project · Ventura California

2019 to 2020

- Developed database entry solutions through creation, adjustment, and quality assurance of database entry forms in Access
- Supervised database architecture for dual purpose of KPI monitoring and expense accrual of contractor assets
- Optimized efficiency of third-party contractor data by defining relationships between database tables
- · Use GIS tools in Power BI to visualize reports and create dynamic dashboards, in conjunction with Access Database
- Leveraged Tableau, Power BI, Access and Excel and internal data to generate biweekly reports on ~607,000 data points

City of Oxnard (contract)

Account Clerk · Oxnard California

2019 to 2019

- Exemplified adaptability by changing to Finance Department needs: Mail Room, Account Receivable, Payroll, Purchasing
- Identified and monitored KPI within mail delivery system in order to optimize results and operate at 40 per cent efficiency
- Developed excel workbooks and structures using advanced excel formulas to clean and restructure data for rapid human query response and account reconciliations
- Delivered forward facing customer support throughout accounting process of local hospitality tax and managed vendor queries, requisitions, encumbrances and purchase orders

American Income Life

Supervising Agent · Ventura County California

2018 to 2019

STEMful and Bricks 4 Kidz

Curriculum Development Team Lead · San Francisco California

2017 to 2017

- Systematized first proactive restorative justice practices for classroom conflict management
- Expanded Program's reach by adapting 4 inaugural Spanish classes and 5 weekly camps
- Researched and adapted STEM enrichment activities with diverse complexity
- Introduced and teaching seminar based on growth mindset promotion with educators for greater engagement and success within students

ARISE High School

Mathematics and Chemistry Teacher · Oakland California

2013 to 2016

- Planned, developed and executed all aspects of the curriculum, with content aligned to Common Core and Next Generation Science Standards
- Led STEM cultural paradigm shift of subject matter, leading to 97 per cent student success rate
- Innovated use of CRM software to streamline success monitoring and communication between students, parents and educators
- Shared lasting relationships through mathematics with educators and students